

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

7443 Charlotte St, Kansas City, MO 64131

□ 816-668-8654 | **☑** jon.david.baker@gmail.com | **※** www.jdbaker.net

Summary.

I recently completed the Full Stack Web Developer program at Centriq Training. I created multiple MVC projects during the program. My skills are the strongest in the middle-tier and back-end technologies including C# and SQL.

Before enrolling at Centriq, I spent over ten years in the home healthcare field working as direct support staff for individuals with developmental disabilities. I provided direct care to individuals in their homes and in the community helping them live as independently as possible. This experience has made me very service oriented, actively looking for ways to help. It also encouraged active listening and problem sensitivity, knowing when there is a problem without being told about it. Finally, it is a field which promotes critical thinking and deductive reasoning to solve problems.

Those problem-solving skills have led me into development. I have always had an interest in technology and have taken several coding classes over the years, leading to my enrollment in Centriq Training's full-stack web developer track. I enjoy applying my reasoning and problem-solving skills to coding and I am excited to make a career change into the technology field.

Education

Centriq Training Kansas City, MO

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER PROGRAM

January 2019 – May 2019

- Completed intensive 16-week training program including technical and professional skills.
- Created and deployed multiple projects using modern technologies.
- HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, jQueryUI, CSS3, Responsive/Mobile Web Development, Bootstrap
- · Visual Studio, C.NET, ASP.NET, LINQ, MVC, EF
- · ADO.NET, SQL, SQL Server, SSMSE

Truman State University

Kirksville, MO

GENERAL EDUCATION COURSEWORK

2003 - 2006

• Completed general coursework including introductory Computer Science courses.

Projects

www.jdbaker.net

PERSONAL SITE

• Created a personal site to serve as a home for my resume and projects. Included converting a static template to use MVC. All projects below can be found linked on this site.

SpaceX

INDIVIDUAL PROJECT COMPLETED OUTSIDE OF CLASS

- Built a simple ASP.NET MVC application to interact with the SpaceX API.
- The landing page displays a JavaScript countdown to the next launch. The other page displays information about all launches gathered with C in a separate layer of the application that could easily be utilized in another project.

Agency LMS

FINAL PROJECT

- Created a secure data-driven ASP.NET MVC application from design through deployment for managing an employee's progress through a direct support agency's training and education courses.
- Employees can view courses, which are divided into one or more lessons and then check their progress and expiration dates on courses they've completed. Managers can view the progress of the employees under them and are automatically emailed when one of their staff completes a course.

Superheroes, Inc.

Теам Риојест

- Designed a secure data-driven ASP.NET MVC application for a fictional charity offering the community classes taught by superheroes.
- This application was developed in Team Development class at Centriq Training. Students developed their application in an Agile environment, utilizing Scrum ceremonies, Kanban boards, and source control. Students were only permitted to work on this project during school hours over the course of two days.

Work Experience

Community Choice, Inc. Kansas City, MO

DIRECT SUPPORT PROFESSIONAL 2018 - 2019

• Provided in-home care for developmentally disabled individuals. Including monitoring health and wellness and administering medication.

Comfort of Home Healthcare Kansas City, MO

LEAD STAFF

2017 - 2018

2014 - 2017

• Managed staff and coordinated day to day operations of a house providing 24/7 care for multiple clients requiring intensive medical assistance.

Easterseals Midwest Kansas City, MO

MEDICAL SUPPORT INSTRUCTOR

Coordinated activities for clients and advocated for improved patient care leading to improved outcomes.

Community Choice, Inc.Kansas City, MOCOMMUNITY INTEGRATION SPECIALIST2013 - 2014

• Provided social and community support to intellectually disabled clients in independent living.

Alternative Opportunities Kansas City, MO

LEAD STAFF 2010 - 2013

• Supervised staff, created schedules, and provided on-call support in a home providing clients with support for social and life skills.

Nova Center of the Ozarks

Springfield, MO

DIRECT SUPPORT PROFESSIONAL 2006 - 2010

• Assisted developmentally and physically disabled clients with daily living tasks and care.